Minutes_meeting_2025_05_13
*Date: 2025-05-13*
*Time: 13:30*
*Present: Tijn, Jesper, Silvia Gaastra-Nedea, Thomas Roza, Joris Schekkerman*
*Minute taker: Tijn* 
*Purpose of meeting: Discuss our midterm presentation draft and our project proposal.*

There's quite a bit of confusion around the meeting location due to which the meeting is 60 mins late.
Sylvia explains that she has had many problems with her outlook e-mail so she does not get all e-mails.


## Mechanical Enineering group

The Mechanical Engineering (ME) group starts presenting their project proposal. 
They want to use a Gaussian-Mixture Model to predict the distribution of accommodation coefficients. 
Their proposal is the same project proposal they converged on during last meeting.
Jesper makes the point that you want to get away from predicting accomodation coefficients because then you are back to a parametric model.
Sylvia agrees with his point but makes the point that you might need the accommodation coefficient for some tasks still, like calculating energy loss, upscaling your model and non-equilibrium interactions.


## AIES group
#### Things to look into
- Another option for a ML model to explore is density neural network.
- Data for high temperature/ high velocity starts to deviate from the predictions of a GMM, that's why it is interesting to try different models. 

#### Feedback on midterm presentation
Sylvia:
- Most important thing is making the other assessors understand what it is we are working on.
- During the final oral examination you will get a question about another groups project so explain it well enough that the audience will be able to answer questions about your project.
- The point of the midterm presentation is to foster inter-group interaction.
- Add the fact that the Boltzmann equations are difficult to solve.
- The monte Carlo simulation is at the level of the molecules not even true.
- Fluid-wall paramtric models: the Maxwell model has full memory (idk what this means).

- Literature review: models
- # TODO Show a problem from one of the papers -> the fact that the CLL model falls apart in the high temperature high velocity regime (ADD fig 8 from paper 'Modeling rarefied gas-solid surface interactions for Couette
flow with different wall temperatures using an unsupervised machine learning technique')
- Quick point from Jesper: we have to add slide numbers.
- Final report can be handed in to Sylvia after the final presentation. Sylvia is the only one who grades our final report.
- We plan the oral exam with Sylvia and she is fine doing it up to two weeks after the final presentation.
- Add cloud scattering graph to presentation with explanation about computing acc. coefficient with line through cloud.